ANUMAH JOSHUA ENEYE

Junior Full stack Developer

+234 8147 895 020

@ anumahjoshuaeneye@gmail.com

♥ Federal Capital Territory Abuja, Nigeria.

@github.com/Ernie1234

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 5 years of experience in Javascript/JS, Dart, and Python. Led the development of a \$500K research project deemed a "gold standard" by the client. Increase learning and performance after tremendous task successes on leet code and other algorithms problem challenges. Well-acquainted with algorithm and flowchart methodologies.

EDUCATION

B.Tech. in Telecommunication Engineering

Federal University of Technology Minna

iii 11/2017 - Present ♥ Niger State, Nigeria.

GPA 3.4 / 5.0

EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer

Legacy.EA

= 2017 - 2020 Niger state, Nigeria.

Legacy. EA is an national Technology and Graphics Consulting Group with a rapid pace of development and innovative solutions for demanding projects. I work as a still and motion graphic designer here, so times as a 3D designer, responsible for conceptualizing, designing, and editing graphic-related work.

- Trained and led an Agile team of 4 junior graphics designers
- Worked with Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe AfterEffect, Adobe Premier Pro, and Blender to stunning graphical services such as logo designs, vectors, flyers, etc.

Frontend Developer

National Information and Technology Development Agency, Nigeria

NITDA is the official Government body that develops and regulates Information Technology in Nigeria.

- Worked as a frontend developer with the software team as intern at NITDA for a year.
- Trained with and lead by an agile team of 7 full-stack developers
- Simultaneously created & maintained scheduled jobs in Node.js for space maintenance and daily backups of system and user databases for 10
- Increased company revenue by 0.5% within 11 months after developing and implementing application idea for over 20 features
- Designed and Developed UI design for over 15 web app using CSS, HTML, Javascript, and React.

Full Stack Developer

JOWIS Tech

2022 - Present Palo Alto, CA

Jowis tech is a Digital and technological tech startup in Abuja, Niger state, Kwara state, helping companies to thrive on mobile apps, the web, VR/AR and

- Shortened project timeline by 14 months for company's largest customer by managing relationship with 3rd party vendors, saving over \$800
- Led development of \$50K embedded and lot research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client
- Fine-tuned and developed embedded and IoT based on the research with embedded C++, python, and arduino.
- Performed Web Scraping over a catalog of 100K+ school supply products using mainly NodeJS and MongoDB; completed in 2 months
- Developed sophisticated web and mobile apps with react native and next.

SKILLS

Client-Side

HTML CSS JS **Tialwind**

React Readux Toolkit Redux

TypeScript AntDesign MaterialUI

Server-side

Express.js Django **TensorFlow** Sanity.io Next.js NodeJS Redis **MongoDB APIs** HTTP/2

Development & Operations

Jest Contentful

PROJECTS

Blog site

= 08/2020 - 12/2020 Palo Alto, CA https://github.com/Ernie1234/church_site_and_blog OpenFlow protocol-based proactive Firewall in Python and NodeJS.

- Configured static rules using MD-SAL
- Engineered proactive rule evaluation system at OSI layer 7 using POX controller
- Provided flexibility to configure rule using centralised NodeJS based GUI

STRENGTHS

Team Leadership

Introduction to Leadership course by Leadership summit MindShift

Communication

Attended a Communication course at Youth